Sheikh Anas Bilal

anasbilal1122786@gmail.com

+92 312 4497764

👤 Lahore, Pakistan

github.com/AnasBilal10

in linkedin.com/in/anasbilal786

Profile

JavaScript/TypeScript developer with 3 years of experience working on scalable B2B and B2C monolithic and event-driven applications. I have experience in understanding client visual design intent. The main motive is to create and maintain better reusable code bases. Motivated to build software with leading technologies like JavaScript and TypeScript on a larger scale with the best performance experience.

Work Experience

Stewart - Senior Software Engineer

Aug 2023 - Current Lahore Pakistan

- Spearheaded the evolution of the Angular-based front-end architecture, resulting in a 20% improvement in overall performance, and 25% boost in maintainability
- Mentored a team member, contributing to a 30% enhancement in their skill set, and ensuring a team-wide adherence to industry best practices.
- Orchestrated client discussions, translating requirements into technical specifications, and ensuring seamless alignment between client expectations, product features and optimizing performance up to 80%.
- Resolved and Conducted code reviews to ensure adherence to established coding standards, and optimize performance up to 50%.

Rolustech - Software Engineer

July 2021 - June 2023 Lahore Pakistan

 Developed and Maintained 5+ B2B and B2C web Call center portals to reduce the 90% manual effort for creating client complaint tickets using Angular and Nodejs.

Education

University of the Punjab Bachelors in Computer Science

Nov 2017 - June 2021 Lahore, Pakistan

Skills

Languages:

HTML JavaScript, TypeScript Java

Libraries/Frameworks:

Angular (11 - 16) React Js NextJs NestJs RxJs

Redux Firebase

Styling:

Tailwind CSS CSS/SCSS Material UI Chakra UI AntDesign Prime Ng

- Organized telephony services in 2+ applications using event-based programming to achieve the best grand stream calling experience without using any third-party calling SDK.
- Build a Node.js server to make a bridge from Front End to CRM with 90% of the best security services by using middleware functions.
- Applied design patterns MVVM, MVC, and MV to make code 100% clean and concise.
- Made 2+ libraries using Angular 14 to achieve reusability and save manual effort
- Deployed 5+ apps using AWS Elastic Bean, EC2, and S3 bucket.

Projects

PUCIT Mini Olympics

 A competitive sports event management software that overcomes 90% of manual enrollment problems and allows the students to participate in various games offered by the Pucit Sports Society.

AI Bloggers

- Developed a cutting-edge AI chat GPT API integrated blogs website using Next.js 13, Tailwind CSS, and Prisma ORM. with an 85% success rate.
- Leveraged the powerful features of Next.js 13, including server-side rendering (SSR) and static site generation (SSG), to create a high-performance and SEO-friendly web application

Certifications

Participated in multiple web coding competition portals like leetcode, hacker rank

- Angular Basic (HackerRank)
- JavaScript Basic (HackerRank)

Tools: Git Linux Jira